1. Being developed at the top of project IntelliJ IDEA, takes into advantage (almost in its entirety) features of edition, debugging, analysis, refactor among many other categories for developing in an effective way.
它是在 IntelliJ IDEA 项目的基础上进行开发的，考虑到它在开发过程中为编辑、调试、分析、重构等众多功能上提供了更高效的方式。
考虑到IntelliJ IDEA 在开发过程中为编辑、调试、分析、重构等众多功能上提供了更高效的方式，AS选择在IntelliJ IDEA的基础上进行开发。

2. the intention of this article is to serve as media support (there weren't slides) of the talk
这篇文章的用意是作为媒体支持（有没有幻灯片）的谈话
这篇文章的用意是为这次谈话提供媒体支持（这个词总觉得怪怪的）

3. IntelliJ IDEA and, as the result, Android Studio offers solutions finding files, classes, actions.
IntelliJ IDEA，Android Studio提供了查找文件、类和操作的方案
IntelliJ IDEA以及以它为基础的Android Studio都提供了查找文件、类和操作的方案（“as the result”强调递进关系）

4. Bonus:
福利：
优势（会不会好一点）

5. It shows files that have been opened and changed recently.
它可以显示出最近打开编辑过的文件。
它可以显示出最近打开并编辑过的文件。

6. Similarly, the window structure (⌘ + 7), shows the same information but in a permanent way.
同样的,窗口结构(⌘+ 7),但在一个永久的方式显示了相同的信息。
类似的，窗口结构(⌘+ 7)会通过一个常驻窗口（而不是对话框）显示相同的信息。

7. It could be useful after add some declarations place the caret back to the previous edition without using your mouse.
你添加声明后，不需要使用鼠标，光标将会回到你之前编辑的地方，这是很有用的。
当你添加了部分声明后，不使用鼠标就能将光标移回到之前编辑的地方会是一个非常实用的特性

8. The action Last Edit Location (⌘ + ⇧ + ⌫), does exactly that.
回到上一个编辑位置的操作 (⌘ + ⇧ + ⌫)，就得这么做。
回到上一个编辑位置的操作 (⌘ + ⇧ + ⌫)，正是实现上述操作的快捷键。

9. If instead ENTER we press TAB, and if desired method call has the same number of parameters, the new code will be automatically set with the old parameters.
如果我们用TAB键取代ENTER键，而如果想要调用参数个数相同的方法，这些新代码将会自动取代旧的参数。
如果我们用TAB键取代ENTER键，并且我们想要调用的方法与原方法参数个数相同，那么这些新代码将会自动取代旧的参数。

10. Besides, we could print logs with an specific expression, which can be set at the same dialog under the Log Evaluated Expression option. Once again it will suggest sentences of your context with the completion dialog while you are typing the expression.
此外，我们也可以打印打印指定格式的日志，同样可以在对话框下设置Log Evaluated Expression选项。将再次建议你跟根据上文的句子在对话框中完成输入表达式。
此外，我们同样可以在对话框下设置Log Evaluated Expression选项来打印出指定格式的日志。AS将再次提示你根据上文的句子在对话框中完成输入表达式。

11. (You always could read your code btw! :D).
你总是在看着你的代码。
当然你也可以一直读你的代码。（我不知道我这样是不是对的、但是我觉得应该不是“你总是在看着你的代码”的意思）